joomag.com 2018-09-05

# Joomag Privacy Statement

**Updated as of May 14, 2018**

At Joomag, privacy is a priority. This Privacy Policy sets out how Joomag, Inc. and its subsidiaries and affiliated companies ( **“Joomag”** , **“we”** , **“our”** , or **“us”** ) collect and use information from customers and other individuals who access or use our websites, including joomag.com ( **“Sites”** ), our mobile applications ( **“Applications”** ), and/or any of our other sites, products, or services that link to this Privacy Policy (collectively **“Services”** ). By using our Services, you understand that we will collect and use your information as described in this Privacy Policy (collectively **“you”** ). 

If you or your organization has an individual agreement with us, that agreement may have privacy terms that also apply to the information you provide to us under that agreement. Please review the terms in that agreement because they may be different or more restrictive than the terms in this Privacy Policy. 

This Privacy Policy ( **“Policy”** ) does not apply to any third-party websites and apps that you may use, including any that are linked to in our Services. You should review the terms and policies for third-party websites and apps before clicking on any links. 

## Scope of This Policy

In this Policy, personal information means information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person. An identifiable person is one who can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an identifier such as a name, an identification number, location data, and online identifier or to one or more factors specific to his/her physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural or social identity. The use of information collected through our Service shall be limited to the purpose of providing the Service for which the Customer has engaged. 

With the exception of Account and Registration Information (as defined below), Payment Information (as defined below) and other information we collect in connection with your registration or authentication into our Services (as defined below), this Policy does not apply to our security and privacy practices in connection with your access to and use of the Services. These security and privacy practices, including how we protect, collect, and use electronic data, text, messages, communications or other materials submitted to and stored within the Services by you ( **“Service Data”** ), are detailed in and governed by our Terms of Service, available [here](https://www.joomag.com/en/terms), or such other applicable agreement between you and any member of Joomag relating to your access to and use of such Services (collectively referred to as the **“Service Agreement”** ). For the purposes of this Policy, **“Customer”** shall refer to an individual or an entity that has entered into a Service Agreement with us for use of our Services. 

Customers are solely responsible for establishing policies for and ensuring compliance with all applicable laws and regulations, as well as any and all privacy policies, agreements or other obligations, relating to the collection of personal information in connection with the use of our Services by individuals (also referred to as “data subjects”) with whom our Customers interact. If you are an individual who interacts with a Customer using our Services, then you will be directed to contact our Customer for assistance with any requests or questions relating to your personal information. 

We collect information under the direction of our Customers and have no direct relationship with individuals whose personal information we process in connection with our Customer’s use of our Services. If you are an individual who interacts with a Customer using our Services (such as a client of one of our Customers) and would either like to amend your contact information or no longer wish to be contacted by one of our Customers that use our Services, please contact the Customer that you interact with directly. 

We may transfer personal information to companies that help us provide our Services. Transfers to subsequent third parties for these purposes are governed by the Service Agreements with our Customers. 

## Information That You Provide to Us

### **Account and Registration Information**

This refers to any information that you voluntarily submit to us and that identifies you personally, including contact information, such as your name, e-mail address, company name, address, phone number, and other information about yourself or your business. Account and Registration Information can also include information about any transactions, both free and paid, that you enter into on the Sites and Applications, and information about you that is available on the internet, such as from Facebook, LinkedIn, Twitter and Google, or publicly available information that we acquire from service providers. 

### **Payment Information**

We collect and process payment information from you when you purchase or use Services, including credit cards numbers and billing information, using third-party intermediary PCI-compliant service providers. These intermediaries are not permitted to store, retain, or use your billing information for any purpose except for credit card processing on our behalf. 

## Information That We Collect from You

### **When You Visit our Sites or Use our Applications**

When you visit our Sites or use our Applications, some information is automatically collected. This may include information such as the Operating System (OS) running on your device, Internet Protocol (IP) address (which may be used to obtain your geolocation), access times, browser type, time zone, and language, and the website you visited before our Sites. We also collect information about how you use Joomag’s Sites, Applications and Services, including the elements you have interacted with, metadata and other details about these elements, clicks, change states and other user actions. 

### **When You Use our Applications**

We use mobile analytics software to allow us to better understand the functionality of our Applications on your mobile device. This software may record information such as how often you use the application, the events that occur within the application, aggregated usage, performance data, and where the application was downloaded from. In addition to information we collect on our Sites, when you use our Applications we may also collect your city location, device model and version, device identifier (or “UDID”), OS version, and your Joomag credentials. 

We send push notifications from time to time in order to update you about events or promotions. If you no longer wish to receive such communications, you may turn them off at the device level. 

### **Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies**

We and our authorized partners may use cookies and other information gathering technologies for a variety of purposes. These technologies may provide us with personal information, information about devices and networks you utilize to access our Sites, and other information regarding your interactions with our Sites. For detailed information about the use of cookies in the Sites, please read and review our Cookie Policy found [here](https://www.joomag.com/en/cookie-policy). 

We partner with third parties to either display advertising on the Sites or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third-party partners may also use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on our Sites and other sites in order to suggest advertisements based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) (or if located in the European Economic Area you may opt-in the use of cookies, by clicking [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)). 

Web beacons, tags and scripts may be used on our Sites or in email or other electronic communications we send to you. These assist us in delivering cookies, counting visits to our Sites, understanding usage and campaign effectiveness and determining whether an email has been opened and acted upon. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by our third-party service providers on an individual and aggregated basis. 

We use Local Storage Objects (“LSOs”) such as HTML5 to store content information and preferences. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LSOs. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our Sites or to display advertising based upon your web browsing activity use LSOs such as HTML5 to collect and store information. 

### **Logs**

As is true with most websites and services delivered over the Internet, we gather certain information and store it in log files when you interact with our Sites and Services. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses as well as browser type, internet service provider, URLs of referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, information you search for, locale and language preferences, identification numbers associated with your devices, your mobile carrier, and system configuration information. Occasionally, we connect personal information to information gathered in our log files as necessary to improve our Sites and Services. In such a case, we would treat the combined information in accordance with this Policy. 

## Information Collected from Other Sources

### **Information from Third Party Services**

We may also obtain other information, including personal information, from third parties and combine that with information we collect through our Sites and Applications. For example, we may have access to certain information from a third party social media or authentication service if you log into our Services through such a service or otherwise provide us with access to information from the service. Any access that we may have to such information from a third party social media or authentication service is in accordance with the authorization procedures determined by that service. By authorizing us to connect with a third-party service, you authorize us to access and store your name, email address(es), current city, profile picture URL, and other personal information that the third-party service makes available to us, and to use and disclose it in accordance with this Policy. You should check your privacy settings on these third-party services to understand and change the information sent to us through these services. For example, you can log in to the Services using sign-in services provided by Google or an Open ID provider, as further described below. 

### **Single Sign-On**

You can log into certain Services using sign-in services provided by Facebook, Twitter, Google, LinkedIn, Microsoft or an Open ID provider. These services will authenticate your identity, provide you with the option to share certain personal information (such as your name and email address) with us, and pre-populate our registration form. Services like those provided by Facebook give you the option to post information about your activities in the Services to your profile page to share with others within your network. 

## How We Use Information That We Collect

### **General Uses**

We may use the information we collect about you (including personal information, to the extent applicable) for a variety of purposes, including to (a) provide, operate, maintain, improve, and promote the Services; (b) enable you to access and use the Services; (c) process and complete transactions, and send you related information, including purchase confirmations and invoices; (d) send transactional messages, including responses to your comments, questions, and requests; provide customer service and support; and send you technical notices, updates, security alerts, and support and administrative messages; (e) send promotional communications, such as providing you with information about products and services, features, surveys, newsletters, offers, promotions, contests, and events; and provide other news or information about us and our partners. You can opt-out of receiving marketing communications from us by contacting us at privacy@joomag.com or following the unsubscribe instructions included in our marketing communications; (f) process and deliver contest or sweepstakes entries and rewards; (g) monitor and analyze trends, usage, and activities in connection with the Sites, Applications and Services and for marketing or advertising purposes; (h) investigate and prevent fraudulent transactions, unauthorized access to the Services, and other illegal activities; (i) personalize the Sites, Applications and Services, including by providing features or advertisements that match your interests and preferences; and (j) for other purposes for which we obtain your consent. 

### **Legal Basis for Processing (EEA only)**

If you are an individual from the European Economic Area (EEA), our legal basis for collecting and using the personal information will depend on the personal information concerned and the specific context in which we collect it. However, we will normally collect personal information from you only where: (a) we have your consent to do so, (b) where we need the personal information to perform a contract with you (e.g. to deliver the Joomag Services you have requested), or (c) where the processing is in our or a third party’s legitimate interests (and not overridden by your data protection interests or fundamental rights and freedoms). In some cases, we may also have a legal obligation to collect personal information from you, or may otherwise need the personal information to protect your vital interests or those of another person. 

Where we rely on your consent to process the personal information, you have the right to withdraw or decline your consent at any time. Please note that this does not affect the lawfulness of the processing based on consent before its withdrawal. 

If you have any questions about or need further information concerning the legal basis on which we collect and use your personal information, please contact us using the contact details provided further below in section Contacting Joomag. 

## How We Share and Disclose Information

### **Third Party Service Providers and Partners**

We share information, including personal information, with our third-party service providers that we use to provide hosting for and maintenance of our Sites, application development, backup, storage, payment processing, customer support, technical support, analytics and other services for us. These third-party service providers may have access to or process your personal information for the purpose of providing these services for us. We do not permit our third-party service providers to use the personal information that we share with them for their marketing purposes or for any other purpose than in connection with the services they provide to us. 

### **Compliance with Laws and Law Enforcement Requests; Protection of Our Rights**

In certain situations, we may be required to disclose personal information in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. We may disclose personal information to respond to subpoenas, court orders, or legal process, or to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims. We may also share such information if we believe it is necessary in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of our Terms of Service, or as otherwise required by law. 

### **Affiliates**

We may share your information with other companies under common ownership or control with Joomag. These companies use your information as described in this Privacy Policy. 

### **With Your Consent**

Joomag may share personal information with third parties when we have consent to do so. 

### **In the Event of Merger or Sale**

In the event that Joomag is acquired by or merged with a third-party entity, or undergoes a change of control or any form of sale or transfer of some or all of its assets, we reserve the right, in any of these circumstances, to transfer or assign the information that we have collected from users as part of that merger, acquisition, sale, or other change of control. 

## International Transfer of Information Collected

Joomag may transfer your personal information to countries other than the one in which you live. We deploy the following safeguards if Joomag transfers personal information originating from the European Union or Switzerland to other countries not deemed adequate under applicable data protection law: 

## International Data Localization Obligations

If you reside in a jurisdiction that imposes “data localization” or “data residency” obligations (i.e., requiring that personal information of its residents be kept within the territorial boundaries of such jurisdiction), and we become aware of that, we may maintain your personal information within such territorial boundaries, if we are legally obligated to do so. For example, if we learn that you reside in the Russian Federation, we may be required to maintain your personal information there, whether independently or with a local data storage and processing provider. 

You acknowledge and agree that while doing so, we may continue to collect, store and use your personal information elsewhere, including in the United States of America as explained above. 

## Retention of Information

We will retain your personal information for no longer than necessary for the purposes for which it is processed, unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law (such as tax, accounting or other legal requirements). When we have no ongoing legitimate business need to process your personal information, we will either delete or anonymize it, or, if this is not possible (for example, because your personal information has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely store your personal information and isolate it from any further processing until deletion is possible. 

For personal information that we process on behalf of our Customers, we will retain such personal information in accordance with the terms of our agreement with them, subject to applicable law. 

## Your Privacy Rights

Upon request we will provide you with information about whether we hold, or process on behalf of a third party, any of your personal information. To request this information please contact us at privacy@joomag.com. Our Customers may update or change their personal information by going to Account Settings or by contacting support@joomag.com for more detailed instructions. To make a request to have personal information maintained by us returned to you or removed, please email support@joomag.com. Requests to access, change, or remove your information will be handled within thirty (30) days. 

An individual who seeks access to, or who seeks to correct or, amend inaccuracies in, or delete personal information stored or processed by us on behalf of a Customer should direct his/her query to the Customer (the data controller). Upon receipt of a request from one of our Customers for us to remove the data, we will respond to their request within thirty (30) days. We will retain personal information that we store and process on behalf of our Customers for as long as needed to provide the Services to our Customers. We will retain and use this personal information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. 

If you are a Customer or otherwise provide us with personal information in connection with your use of our Sites, Applications or Services, we will delete this information upon your request, provided that, notwithstanding such request, this information may be retained for as long as you maintain an account for our Services, or as needed to provide you with our Services, comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements. 

### **Additional Rights for EEA and Certain Other Territories**

If you are from certain territories (such as the EEA), you may have the right to exercise additional rights available to you under applicable laws, including: 

  * Right of erasure: In certain circumstances, you may have a broader right to erasure of personal information that we hold about you – for example, if it is no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which it was originally collected. Please note, however, that we may need to retain certain information for record keeping purposes, to complete transactions or to comply with our legal obligations. 
  * Right to object to processing: You may have the right to request that Joomag stop processing your personal information and/or to stop sending you marketing communications. 
  * Right to restrict processing: You may have the right to request that we restrict processing of your personal information in certain circumstances (for example, where you believe that the personal information we hold about you is inaccurate or unlawfully held). 
  * Right to data portability: In certain circumstances, you may have the right to be provided with your personal information in a structured, machine readable and commonly used format and to request that we transfer the personal information to another data controller without hindrance. 

If you would like to exercise such rights, please contact us at the contact details in section Contacting Joomag. We will consider your request in accordance with applicable laws. To protect your privacy and security, we may take steps to verify your identity before complying with the request. 

You also have the right to complain to a data protection authority about our collection and use of your personal information. For more information, please contact your local data protection authority. A list of contact details for the EU data protection authorities is available here. 

## Children’s Personal Information

We do not knowingly collect any personal information from children under the age of 13. If you are under the age of 13, please do not submit any personal information through our Sites, Applications or Services. We encourage parents and legal guardians to monitor their children’s Internet usage and to help enforce this Policy by instructing their children never to provide personal information through the Sites, Applications or Services without their permission. If you have reason to believe that a child under the age of 13 has provided personal information to us through the Sites, Applications or Services, please contact us at privacy@joomag.com, and we will use commercially reasonable efforts to delete that information. 

## Data Security

Joomag implements security measures designed to protect your personal information against unauthorized access or unauthorized alteration, disclosure or destruction. Other measures include internal reviews of our data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures, as well as physical security measures to guard against unauthorized access to systems where we store personal information. 

We endeavor to restrict access to personal information to Joomag employees, contractors and agents who need to know that information in order to operate, develop or improve our services. These individuals are bound by confidentiality obligations and are required to meet these obligations. 

If Joomag learns of a security systems breach, then we may attempt to notify you electronically so that you can take appropriate protective steps. Joomag may post a notice on the website if a security breach occurs. Depending on where you live, you may have a legal right to receive notice of a security breach in writing. To receive a free written notice of a security breach you should notify us at  [privacy@joomag.com](mailto:privacy@joomag.com). 

For learning more about our Security Practices click [here](https://www.joomag.com/en/security-practices). 

## Changes and Updates to this Policy

Please revisit this page to stay aware of any changes. In general, we only use your personal information in the manner described in the Privacy Policy in effect when we received that personal information. Your continued use of Joomag constitutes your agreement to this Privacy Policy and any future revisions. 

For revisions to this Privacy Policy that may be materially less restrictive on our use or disclosure of personal information you have provided to us, we will make reasonable efforts to notify you and obtain your consent before implementing revisions with respect to such information. 

## Contacting Joomag

Please contact Joomag with any questions or comments about this Policy, your personal information, and our third-party disclosure practices or your consent choices by email:  [privacy@joomag.com](mailto:privacy@joomag.com), or at: 

Joomag, Inc.  
Attn: Privacy Officer  
75 E Santa Clara St  
San Jose, CA 95113, United States 

We will respond to your inquiry within 30 days of its receipt.
